Guide to the Rogers Family Papers 1614-1950 (bulk 1831-1950) MS 523
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
- Series II: Papers of the Rogers Family, 1636-1950
  - Subseries III: Genealogical research, 1872 - 1965
    - Letters to Derby Rogers 1902-1919 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Letters to Derby Rogers 1920-1925 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Letters to Derby Rogers 1925-1927 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Letters to Derby Rogers 1928-1929 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Letters to Derby Rogers 1929-1945 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Letters to Katherine R. Rogers, 1909-1939 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Letters, notes, and correspondence relating to genealogy (dated), 1834-1946 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Letters, notes, and correspondence relating to genealogy (undated) (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Genealogical notes and writings on the Rogers Family (folder 1 of 3), Undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Genealogical notes and writings on the Rogers family (folder 2 of 3) (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Genealogical notes and writings on the Rogers family (folder 3 of 3) (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Copies of ancient English family Wills & Rogers family wills, 1546, 1562, 1543, 1567, 1571, 1579, 1572, 1578, 1595, 1605, 1608, 1609, 1615, 1620, 1633, 1637, 1639, 1654 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      From the New England Historic Genealogical Society, Boston, Mass. includes the wills of families: Symonds, Mohun, Lechland, and Hide.
    - Obituaries, 1904-1927 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Handwritten family trees of the Rogers family (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Handwritten volumes of Rogers family genealogy (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Bound volume concerning the Rogers family ancestory and lineage, Undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Rogers family genealogies (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Genealogies of families relating to the Rogers family (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Draft copy of book on Bromfield family history (folder 1 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Draft copy of book on Bromfield family history (folder 2 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Second draft copy of book on Bromfield family history (folder 1 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Second draft copy of book on Bromfield family history (folder 2 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Volumes relating to the Derby family of Salem, 1921 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Copy of a genealogical book on the Derby family by F.T. Pope (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Jewett family history (folder 1 of 2), 1908, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Jewett family history (folder 2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Two copies of Registers of Families settled at the town of Medford, MASS., 1855 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Publications about Boston and Salem, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - New England magazines; Pamphlet relating to Old Chelmsford, England, 1869 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Puritan Society pamphlet, 1911; Early Wills of Coffin, 1893, 1855, 1867, 1906, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Publications relating to various people (relatives?), 1855, 1872 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Appraisal of the estate of Dr. John O. Perry, Boston; Genealogical papers of the Rogers family, April 6 1927 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Newspaper articles relating to the Rogers family (Oversize OS small, Folder Rogers OS1)
    - Bound volume 1 and copies of Country Life Magazine, 1921 (Oversize OS Small, Folder Rogers OS2)
    - Accompanying letters, notes, and articles from bound volume no.1 (Oversize OS Small, Folder Rogers OS3)
    - Drafts of Rogers family trees (Oversize OS large, Folder Rogers OS4)
- Series III: Photocopies of Rogers Family Documents, 1732-1904 (Box 12)
  This series consists of photocopies of original documents that remained in the Rogers Family's hands with the donation of this material. Primarily comprised of the papers of Henry Bromfield Rogers, including an extensive journal dating from 1825 to 1827 and a few business papers relating to his work for the Sanitary Commission, this series also includes a few letters from John Rogers, Jr., his will, and an article he wrote about the unveiling of his Statue of Abraham Lincoln. Also contained are a few letters by Daniel Denison Rogers.